<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bluetooth on 20162-K3171 - Interaction Design: Interactivity: Journal</title>
    <link>https://sunflowr.github.io/20162-k3171-journal/tags/bluetooth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bluetooth on 20162-K3171 - Interaction Design: Interactivity: Journal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2016 21:24:07 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sunflowr.github.io/20162-k3171-journal/tags/bluetooth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Pre-week2</title>
      <link>https://sunflowr.github.io/20162-k3171-journal/2016/09/04/pre-week2</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2016 21:24:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sunflowr.github.io/20162-k3171-journal/2016/09/04/pre-week2</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;fridays-work-material-for-creating-an-spatial-experience&#34;&gt;Fridays work: Material for creating an spatial experience&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the sources below and continue to explore how this can help you create a spatial experience. Perhaps a productive way to think about the material when you read it is to relate it to coupling (Time, Location, Direction, Dynamics, Modality, and Expression). In that way you will perhaps get a feeling for what kind of experiences Bluetooth can resonate with more easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;readings&#34;&gt;Readings:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electromagnetic_radiation&#34;&gt;Electromagnetic radiation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radio_wave&#34;&gt;Radio wave&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bluetooth&#34;&gt;Bluetooth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bluetooth_low_energy&#34;&gt;BLE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Birch&#34;&gt;Birch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MAC_address&#34;&gt;MAC-address&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IP_address&#34;&gt;IP-address&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;electromagnetic-radiation&#34;&gt;Electromagnetic radiation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bluetooth is electromagnetic waves. Read the introduction. How does sound differ from electromagnetic waves?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soundwaves are not electromagnetic radiation. At the lower end of the electromagnetic spectrum, about 20 Hz to about 20 kHz, are frequencies that might be considered in the audio range. However, electromagnetic waves cannot be directly perceived by human ears. Sound waves are instead the oscillating compression of molecules. To be heard, electromagnetic radiation must be converted to pressure waves of the fluid in which the ear is located (whether the fluid is air, water or something else).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;radio-wave&#34;&gt;Radio wave&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radio waves are a type of electromagnetic radiation with wavelengths in the electromagnetic spectrum longer than infrared light. Radio waves have frequencies as high as 300 GHz to as low as 3 kHz, though some definitions describe waves above 1 or 3 GHz as microwaves, or include waves of any lower frequency. At 300 GHz, the corresponding wavelength is 1 mm (0.039 in), and at 3 kHz is 100 km (62 mi). Like all other electromagnetic waves, they travel at the speed of light. Naturally occurring radio waves are generated by lightning, or by astronomical objects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radio_wave&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radio_wave&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radio_wave#Propagation&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radio_wave#Propagation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;bluetooth&#34;&gt;Bluetooth&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bluetooth is a wireless technology standard for exchanging data over short distances (using short-wavelength UHF radio waves in the ISM band from 2.4 to 2.485 GHz[4]) from fixed and mobile devices, and building personal area networks (PANs). Invented by telecom vendor Ericsson in 1994,[5] it was originally conceived as a wireless alternative to RS-232 data cables. It can connect several devices, overcoming problems of synchronization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bluetooth&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bluetooth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;natural-and-human-made-materials&#34;&gt;Natural and human made materials&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think and Discuss: What are the differences and similarities between natural materials as Birch and human made ones as Bluetooth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering that humans are part of nature it must thus mean that anything we do can be seen as natural.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>