<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>20162-K3171 - Interaction Design: Interactivity: Journal</title>
    <link>https://sunflowr.github.io/20162-k3171-journal/tags/presentation/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on 20162-K3171 - Interaction Design: Interactivity: Journal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Released under the MIT license&lt;br&gt;Powered by [Hugo](//gohugo.io/) with the [Type Theme](//github.com/digitalcraftsman/hugo-type-theme)</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://sunflowr.github.io/20162-k3171-journal/tags/presentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Module4 presentation</title>
      <link>https://sunflowr.github.io/20162-k3171-journal/post/20161027/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 19:48:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sunflowr.github.io/20162-k3171-journal/post/20161027/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We had decided on meeting up a few minutes earlier to test things out and calibrate sensors and setup Ableton and Max for Live. I was a bit late because I had problem finding the DVI/HDMI adapter for the computer, but we still managed to do the things we planned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the presentation went fine for most part. I agreed with the feedback that it would have been much better if we had said the text instead of showing it in the video (see Video).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also seemed like we failed to convey that we tried lots of different combinations of how we used the sensors before ending up were we currently are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should have been more clear about important finding such as the breaking point were realized best practice (for us in this special case) for using the accelerometer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we didn&amp;rsquo;t get any real critic of the openness, tightness or ambiguity we assume that we applied it in a good way in the interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learnings&#34;&gt;Learnings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Through the sketching process we realized that the best way to use the accelerometer is to stop thinking of it as absolute values and instead use the shifting values over time to to either increase or decrease something.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another important realisation is that &amp;ldquo;less is more&amp;rdquo; still holds true. After presenting the current sketch to the teachers a few days before the presentation - thinking that we had something that felt good - we quickly realized that the use of so many different sensors and sounds in combination created something very complex and hard to control. The only reason we thought it was &amp;ldquo;ok&amp;rdquo; was because we were so use to it and knew how it worked. After that we tried simplifying the design but removing sounds and simplifying the usage of the accelerometer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to setup and explain the limitations (rules) to the person interacting with the artifact - if there&amp;rsquo;s something that could break it. As an example if the person using the chair didn&amp;rsquo;t sit on it with the Y-axis of the accelerometer facing forward when sitting down, the readings would be all wrong.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;demonstrative-video&#34;&gt;Demonstrative video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shows a few examples of the sketch-process as well as the current state of the design.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/xljvnld_xqk&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/xljvnld_xqk&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/xljvnld_xqk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sunflowr.github.io/20162-k3171-journal/20162-k3171-journal/img/20161026/Interactivity1Project.zip&#34;&gt;Ableton Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/xljvnld_xqk&#34;&gt;Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation of Module2</title>
      <link>https://sunflowr.github.io/20162-k3171-journal/post/20160929/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:08:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sunflowr.github.io/20162-k3171-journal/post/20160929/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We meet up in the morning to test so everything worked, of course it didn&amp;rsquo;t.
One important wire was broken and needed replacement and one vibrator wire needed to be re-attached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we confirmed everything as working we went to the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;presentation&#34;&gt;Presentation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While a bit nervous the presentation went fine. They seemed to think it was an interesting concept. Nothing really negative to say about it. They suggested taking a step back from our context and see in what other areas/context the idea could be used - to explore outside the context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They seemed to like the idea of giving one of the user all the control (touch) while the other loosing the control (user with vibrator) having to rely on the other user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;end-result&#34;&gt;End result&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://sunflowr.github.io/20162-k3171-journal/20162-k3171-journal/img/20160929/sensor.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sensor clothing&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://sunflowr.github.io/20162-k3171-journal/20162-k3171-journal/img/20160929/vibrator.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;vibrator clothing&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sunflowr/school-stuff-20162-k3171---module2/&#34;&gt;github code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Module 1 final thoughts</title>
      <link>https://sunflowr.github.io/20162-k3171-journal/post/20160920/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 22:07:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sunflowr.github.io/20162-k3171-journal/post/20160920/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was the presentation. We meet up an hour before to sync and it was discovered that there was some issues in the prototype. Apparently something had changed in the data that we hadn&amp;rsquo;t taken into consideration (a registered device without any discovered devices). After fixing this we had a small sync and some coffee. After that it was time for presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;presentation&#34;&gt;Presentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it seemed hard to understand our concept at first, I felt that the audience grasped somewhat in the end what we tried to explore. I guess that we had not found a good way of describing our prototype or the findings. Our concept was a bit abstract and on a meta level where we were more focusing on the idea of space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had some critique on the concepts use of bluetooth which I can in hindsight understand, as we focused more on exploring space and how things are interpreted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;things-to-consider-for-the-future&#34;&gt;Things to consider for the future&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do we present the findings?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sunflowr/20162-k3171-module1&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://k3171-test.firebaseapp.com/&#34;&gt;app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>